

Postdoctoral Scholar, NSD, LBNL

CONTACT INFO

Work Address: Nuclear Science Division, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory,

1 Cyclotron Road, Building 70 Rooms 231, Berkeley, CA 94720, USA

Email Address: yuxunguo@lbl.gov (also at youuungx@gmail.com)

Phone Number: 240-413-8190

OBJECTIVES

I am currently a postdoctoral researcher in the nuclear theory group at the Nuclear Science Division, Lawrence Berkeley National Lab, and also part of the Quark-Gluon Tomography (QGT) topical collaboration. I am interested in the 3-dimensional structure of nucleons and physics related to the generalized parton distributions (GPDs). I focus on studies related to GPDs with high energy exclusive processes such as deeply virtual Compton scattering, deeply virtual meson production and threshold heavy meson production e.t.c. My research covers from the theoretical aspects of GPDs, e.g., the nucleon spin sum rule, to more numerical studies such as developing programs for numerical extraction of GPDs.

PERSONNAL EXPERIENCE

APPOINTMENT

Postdoc — Lawrence Berkeley National Lab.

Nuclear Theory Group, Nuclear Science Division

Host: Dr. Feng Yuan

Visitor — Lawrence Berkeley National Lab.

Nuclear Theory Group, Nuclear Science Division

Host: Dr. Feng Yuan

Sep. 2023 - Present



Apr. 2023 - Aug. 2023



EDUCATION

Ph. D. — University of Maryland, College Park

Maryland Center for Fundamental Phycics, Dept. of Physics

Advisor: Prof. Xiangdong Ji

Dissertation: Unraveling the Nucleon 3D Structure

from Experiment, Lattice, and Global Analysis

Aug. 2018 - May 2023



B. S. — Tsinghua University, Beijing, China

Department of Physics

Advisor: Prof. Hong-Jian He

Average GPA: 91/100, ranking 6/52.

Aug. 2014 - Jul. 2018



HONORS, AWARDS AND ACTIVITIES

HONORS AND AWARDS

CY2023 Ralph Myers & Friends of Physics Award (Outstanding Teaching Assistant)

CY2021-2022 JSA/Jefferson Lab Graduate Fellowship

CY2021-2022 Center for Nuclear Femtography Graduate Fellowship

CY2018 University of Maryland Physics Graduate Program Dean's Fellowship

CY2015—2018 Tsinghua Xuetang Talents Physics Program

ACTIVITIES

2022 Hampton University Graduate Studies (HUGS) Summer Program at JLab 2022 TMD Collaboration Winter School at Santa Fe

TEACHING AND MENTORING

MENTORING

Jinghong Yang (Graduate student at UMD)
 Sep. 2022 – Present
 For several projects on near-threshold J/ψ photo-productions and the GUMP program for the global analysis of GPDs

• Jinchen He (Graduate student at UMD) Sep. 2022 – Present

For his candidacy projects on "Effective Field Theory for Positronium in Relativistic

Motion"

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Discussion + Grader	$\operatorname{PHYS411}$ - Intermediate Electricity and Magnetism (2022 Fall)	
Lab section	PHYS271 - General Physics III Lab. (2020 & 2021 Fall)	
Lab section	PHYS271-WB - General Physics Lab. 2020 Summer	
Lab section	PHYS260 - General Physics II 2020 Summer	
Grader	PHYS371 - Modern Physics (2020 Spring)	
Grader	PHYS420 - Principles of Modern Physics (2019 & 2020 Spring)	
Grader	PHYS402 - Quantum Physics II (2019 Spring)	
Lab section	PHYS261 - General Physics II Lab. (2018 & 2019 Fall)	

SEMINARS

1.	Hadron Ion Tea (HIT) Seminar at LBNL	Oct. 10th, 2023	
	Probing the GFFs of the nucleon from near-threshold heavy quarkonium photo-production		
2.	Zhongbo Kang Group Seminar at UCLA Unraveling the 3D structure of nucleon	Mar. 9th, 2023	
3.	CFNS Seminar at Stony Brook University Unraveling the 3D structure of nucleon	Nov. 10th, 2022	
4.	Nuclear Theory Seminar at University of Maryland Unraveling the 3D structure of nucleon	Oct. 13th, 2022	
5.	JLab Theory Seminar GPDs and nucleon spin structures	Apr. 25th, 2022	
6.	CNF Seminar Higher order kinematical effects in DVCS	Sep. 29th, 2021	
INVITED TALKS			
1.	2023 QGT collaboration meeting at Temple Milestone progress of Global Analysis on GUMP	Sep. $08 - 09$, 2023	
2.	ECT*-APCTP Joint Workshop: Exploring resonance structure with transition GPDs Global GPD extraction and parametrisation	Aug. 21 - 25, 2023	
3.	CNF GPD global analysis Workshop Moment parameterization of GPDs and global analysis	Jun. 12 – 14, 2023	
4.	3DPartons Workshop GUMP GPDs global analysis	Oct. 26 - 28, 2022	
5.	Opp. with JLab Energy and Luminosity Upgrade at ECT GUMP fitting of GPDs	* Sep. 26 - 30, 2022	
6.	J/Psi and Beyond at JLab Near-Threshold J/psi Production and Gravitational Form Factors	Aug. 16 - 17, 2022	
7.	Twds impvd hadron femtography w. hard excl. reactions GPDs through Universal Moments Parameterization	Jul. 18 – 22, 2022	
8.	The Next Generation of 3D Imaging at JLab GPDs through Universal Moments Parameterization	Jul. 07 – 08, 2022	

CONTRIBUTED TALKS

Global analysis of GPDs with GUMP program

- The 25th International Spin Symposium (SPIN 2023) Sep. 24 29, 2023
 Threshold heavy quarkonium production and GPDs at large skewness

 The 25th International Spin Symposium (SPIN 2023) Sep. 24 29, 2023
- 3. Precision QCD Predictions for ep Physics at the EIC (II) Sep. 18 22, 2023 Global analysis of GPDs with GUMP program—near forward and beyond
- 4. **2023 QGT collaboration meeting at Temple** Sep. 08 09, 2023 Parameterization and extraction of GPDs from small to larger skewness
- 5. **APS April meeting virtual 2023** Apr. 24 26, 2023 GPDs through Universal Moments Parameterization at non-zero skewness
- 6. APS GHP workshop 2023 Apr. 12 14, 2023 GPDs through Universal Moments Parameterization at non-zero skewness
- 7. **DIS 2023 at MSU**Mar. 27 31, 2023

 GPDs through Universal Moments Parameterization at non-zero skewness
- 8. APS DNP meeting 2022 Oct. 27 30, 2022

 GPDs through Universal Moments Parameterization
- 9. **APS April meeting 2022** Apr. 09 12, 2022 Higher order kinematical effects in DVCS
- 10. APS DNP meeting 2021 Oct. 11 14, 2021
 QCD analysis of near-threshold photon-proton production of heavy quarkonium
 11. 2nd PSQ@EIC: Precision studies on QCD at EIC Jul. 19 23, 2021
- QCD analysis of near-threshold photon-proton production of heavy quarkonium
- 12. QCD evolution workshop 2021 at UCLA May 10 14, 2021 QCD analysis of near-threshold photon-proton production of heavy quarkonium
- 13. APS April meeting 2021 Apr. 17 20, 2021

 Twist-three GPDs and transverse angular momentum sum rules

PUBLICATION LIST

CHECK MY INSPIREHEP.NET OR GOOGLE SCHOLAR PAGES FOR THE MOST RECENT UPDATES.

ARTICLES

- 1. <u>Y. Guo</u>, X. Ji and F. Yuan, Proton's gluon GPDs at large skewness and gravitational form factors from near threshold heavy quarkonium photo-production, 2308.13006
- Y. Guo, X. Ji, Y. Liu and J. Yang, Updated analysis of near-threshold heavy quarkonium production for probe of proton's gluonic gravitational form factors, Phys. Rev. D 108 (2023) 034003 [2305.06992]
- 3. Y. Guo, X. Ji, M.G. Santiago, K. Shiells and J. Yang, Generalized parton distributions through universal moment parameterization: non-zero skewness case, JHEP 05 (2023) 150 [2302.07279]
- 4. <u>Y. Guo</u>, X. Ji and K. Shiells, Generalized parton distributions through universal moment parameterization: zero skewness case, JHEP **09** (2022) 215 [2207.05768]
- 5. <u>Y. Guo</u>, X. Ji, B. Kriesten and K. Shiells, *Twist-three cross-sections in deeply virtual Compton scattering*, *JHEP* **06** (2022) 096 [2202.11114]
- 6. K. Shiells, <u>Y. Guo</u> and X. Ji, On extraction of twist-two Compton form factors from DVCS observables through harmonic analysis, JHEP **08** (2022) 048 [2112.15144]
- 7. <u>Y. Guo</u>, X. Ji and K. Shiells, *Higher-order kinematical effects in deeply virtual Compton scattering*, *JHEP* **12** (2021) 103 [2109.10373]
- 8. <u>Y. Guo</u>, X. Ji and Y. Liu, *QCD Analysis of Near-Threshold Photon-Proton Production of Heavy Quarkonium*, *Phys. Rev. D* **103** (2021) 096010 [2103.11506]
- 9. Y. Guo, X. Ji and K. Shiells, Novel twist-three transverse-spin sum rule for the proton and related generalized parton distributions, Nucl. Phys. B 969 (2021) 115440 [2101.05243]
- 10. X. Chen, W.Z. Chua, <u>Y. Guo</u>, Y. Wang, Z.-Z. Xianyu and T. Xie, *Quantum Standard Clocks in the Primordial Trispectrum*, *JCAP* **05** (2018) 049 [1803.04412]

CONTRIBUTED REPORTS

- 1. A. Accardi et al., Strong Interaction Physics at the Luminosity Frontier with 22 GeV Electrons at Jefferson Lab, 2306.09360
- 2. V.D. Burkert et al., Precision studies of QCD in the low energy domain of the EIC, Prog. Part. Nucl. Phys. 131 (2023) 104032 [2211.15746]

PERSONAL SKILLS

Languages Mandarin(native), English (fluent)

Programming Mathematica, Python, C++, LATEX

Yuxun Guo Curriculum Vitae 5 of 5